This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance to real persons, groups or events is purely coincidental.
Please enjoy your meal.
ごゆっくり
What's the matter?
なにか
Nothing. I just didn't think you literally meant tea.
あっいや　茶というのは本当にお茶だとは思いませんでした
Don't worry. It's my treat.
安心して　払いは持つよ
はあ
So Nakajou's theory didn't work?
中城は駄目だったのか
Nor Haba's?
羽場も
That's right.
はい
How about Sawakiguchi's?
では沢木口も
I'm afraid it was no good either.
無理だと思います
そうか
I see.
My apologies.
残念ですが
社交辞令ならいらない
No need for formalities.
But I would like to hear what was wrong with their theories.
では聞かせてほしい　彼らのどこがまずかった
Firstly, the problem with Nakajou's theory was...
まず　中城先輩の案ですが
Bored, sitting on the windowsill,
退屈な窓辺に吹き込む風に
I frown at the wind to hide my awkwardness
顔を顰めたのは照れくさ　その裏返し
Hyouka
KamiGami
@ 湮·Molly／小然·酸菜／喵儿·小冷／时末·竭力而为
I nod uncertainly as I shape
曖昧に頷く掌の今日
the future in my hands feeling mighty
描いてる自分は少し大袈裟で
I feel that the wind is bringing change
何かが変わりそうな気がしているよ
心に呼びかける君のせいだね
I guess that's your fault for calling out to my heart
曇り空覗いた予感
The cloudy sky tells a tale of what's to come
Spread our wings with more courage than ever before
手を伸ばそう　いつよりも力強い勇気で
光も影もまだ遠くで
Light and dark are still vague in the distance
but still we want to know the reason behind kindness
それでも僕らは優しさの理由が知りたい
No one so far has ever reached
今は誰の名前でもない
the shining distance far beyond
輝きの彼方へ
Let's get there before the past takes it all
全部過去になる前に見つけに行こう
Tea Shop
1-2-3
And that's why Sawakiguchi's theory doesn't work either.
だから沢木口先輩の案も採れないと考えました
I see.
そうか
Out of Sight, Out of Mind
万人的盲点
Who refuted Nakajou's theory?
中城の案を否定したのは誰だった
I did.
俺です
As well as Haba's and Sawakiguchi's?
では　羽場と沢木口についても
That's right.
そうです
When I asked you to solve this mystery, you told me not to have weird expectations.
君は最初　私があの事件を解いてくれと言った時
妙な期待は困ると言ったな
けれど君は中城たちの案をことごとく葬った
And yet, you have refuted all their theories –
just as I secretly expected.
私が内心そうなると思った通りに
You expected this to happen?
思った通りに
彼らは結局器じゃない
They weren't cut out for the job.
It's been clear to me from the beginning that they lack the skills necessary to solve this mystery.
あの問題を解くのに必要な技術が彼らにないことは最初から分かっていた
So this was all a charade? Then—
あれは茶碗ですか　なら
無論　彼らが無能だとは言わない
Of course, I'm not saying they are talentless. They all have valuable skills.
得難い技能を持っている
But those skills are of no use to them in solving this difficult—
だが　だからといってそれが今回の難局の役に立つわけではない
Then why—
だったらなぜ
もし君が　もし君がいなければ
Without your assistance, we would need to accept one of their theories instead,
私たちは彼らの案のうちどれかを採用し
and the project would fail in the worst possible way.
結局企画は最悪の形で失敗しただろう
冷徹ですね
You're cold and realistic. A bit too much so.
それに非情だ
If required, I can be.
必要ならそうする
But I have one person on whom I can place my expectations.
だが　期待する人物なら一人いる
私はその人物の力を三人から聞いていた
I have heard of his skill from three persons.
一人は千反田える　一人は学外の人間
One is Chitanda Eru. One is someone from outside the school.
そしてもう一人は遠垣内将司
The last is Tougaito Masashi.
その人物なら　あのビデオの探偵役を勤められるかもしれない
This person would be our best choice to play the detective,
or so we thought.
そう思っていた
It was you, not the Classics Club, who I've been after from the start.
最初から君が目当てだった　古典部などではなく
Oreki,
折木くん　私は君がこれまでの一件で
I think you have already proven your abilities in this case.
君自身の技術を証明したと考える
You are...
君は特別よ
extraordinary.
You are extraordinary.
そこでもう一度頼みたい
I'd like to ask you once again.
Oreki, please lend class 2-F your aid,
折木くん　どうか二年Ｆ組に力を貸して
and find the solution to our movie's mystery.
あのビデオの正解を見つけて欲しい
俺に技術など　ただ運がよかっただけです
I don't have that kind of skill.
It was just luck.
歯痒いな
How frustrating.
では一つ話をしよう　座興と思って聞いてほしい
Very well. Please listen to my story.
Consider it just for fun.
とある運動部に補欠がいた
In a certain sports club there was a substitute player.
She trained as hard as she could to become a full player, but she was never allowed to.
補欠はレギュラーになろうと　きわめて激しい努力したが
レギュラーにはなれなかった
This was because the club had many other people with much more skill than she did.
そのクラブには　その補欠よりもずっと有能な人材が揃っていたから
There was even one player who could only be described as a genius.
その中でも天性の才の持ち主がいた
Needless to say, the difference between her and the genius was like night and day.
無論補欠の技量とは天と地の開きがあった
彼女はある大会で非常に優れた活躍をし　ＭＶＰにも選ばれた
The genius did so well in a competition that she was named MVP.
Winner
Then she was asked the following question in an interview:
インタビュアーが彼女に訊いた
"That was amazing. What's your secret?"
「大活躍でしたね　秘訣は何ですか」と
Her answer?
彼女はこう答えた
ただ運がよかっただけです
"I was just lucky."
この答えは　その補欠にはあまりに辛辣に響いたと思うけど　どう
I think that answer would have been very painful for the substitute player to hear.
What do you think?
誰でも自分を自覚するべきだ
People should take pride in their own abilities.
Otherwise, think about how those on the sidelines must feel.
でないと　見ている側が馬鹿馬鹿しい
Am I really...
俺は特別なのか
extraordinary?
俺は俺自身を本当に正しく　見積もっているのか
Could I have erred in my self-assessment?
信じて　いいのだろうか
Can I really believe in myself?
Irisu, I—
入須先輩　俺は
It's not like you to go to school on a holiday. What gives?
珍しいね　奉太郎が休日の学校に自発的に行くなんて
何か用でも
Something you've gotta do?
Can't I go to school without having something I need to do?
俺は用がないと学校にも行けないのか
It's just unusual, that's all.
いいや　ただそぐわないねえ
入須先輩から勅令を受けた
I received a direct order from Irisu.
I need to figure out Kaitou's murderer.
海藤殺しの犯人を特定する
へえまさかね　奉太郎が
No way! You?
Oreki Houtarou is helpful and compassionate.
折木奉太郎は義に厚く情が深いんだ
I couldn't quite catch that. Come again?
よく聞こえなかったよ　もう一回
でも随分な心境の変化だね
That's quite different from your usual creed.
今度も原因は千反田さんかい
Is this because of Chitanda again?
No.
いや
じゃあどんな理由が
Then why?
やらなくてもいいことならやらない
"I don't do anything I don't have to."
それが奉太郎のモットーじゃないか
I thought that was your motto.
里志
Satoshi...
うん
お前は　お前にしかできないことがあると思うか
Do you feel like there's anything that only you can do?
Nope.
ないね
Nothing?
ない
Didn't I tell you I have no talents?
言わなかったっけ　僕には才能がないって
たとえば　僕はシャーロキアンに憧れてる
For instance, I look up to Sherlockians, but I can't become one myself.
でも　僕はそれにはなれないんだ
僕には深遠なる知識の迷宮にとことん分け入っていこうという気概が
I lack that vital spirit needed to delve into the unfathomable maze of knowledge.
決定的に欠けている
If Mayaka took an interest in Holmes,
もし摩耶花がホームズに興味を傾ければ　保証していい
mark my words,
三ヶ月で僕は抜かれるね
she'd outdo me in three months.
I just sample each genre long enough to say I've been there.
いろんなジャンルの玄関先をちょっと覗いて
パンフレットにスタンプを押してまわる
それが僕にできるせいぜいのことさ
That's about the most I could do. I couldn't be an expert on anything.
第一人者にはなれないよ
分かったよ
But I get it.
入須先輩に乗せられたね
Irisu got you into it.
ところがやっぱり危ぶむわけだ　自分の素質を
I can see why you'd feel unsure about your own skills.
お前は疑わないな　自分を
You never doubt yourself.
まあね
Oh well.
I'm gonna go on ahead.
僕は先に行ってるよ
摩耶花も学校に来てるはずだから　声を掛けとく
Mayaka's probably at the school too, so I'll drop by to say hi.
里志
Satoshi!
お前がどう思っているか知らんが
I don't know how you look at yourself, but I think more of you than that.
俺はお前をもう少し高く買うぞ
なろうと思えばお前はいつか　日本でも指折りのシャーロキアンになれると思う
If you put your mind to it, you could become the greatest Sherlockian in Japan one day.
シャーロキアンより心惹かれるものは　いくらでもあるさ
There are things more attractive than being a Sherlockian.
それにしても
But still...
I'm envious.
羨ましい限りだね
まったく
Really.
Earth Sci. Prep. room
Oreki voluntarily coming in on a holiday? What is this madness?!
な　夏休みなのに折木が自主的に学校に来るなんて
来たら悪いか
Is that a problem?
It's ominous! Like it's foreshadowing some natural disaster!
悪いわ　天変地異の前触れみたいで気持ち悪い
謎解きをする気になってな
I felt like solving some mysteries.
あんたが　何で
You? Why?
さては入須先輩に何か垂らしこまれたわね
Could it be because a certain person called Irisu coaxed you into it?
摩耶花も鋭いね
You're sharp, Mayaka.
まあいい
Whatever.
By the way, how did it go yesterday?
それより　昨日はあれからどうだった
ちーちゃんのこと
You mean with Chi?
She made it home somehow,
どうにか帰れたみたいだけど
but when I called her this morning, she was suffering from a hangover.
今朝電話してみたら　二日酔いで寝込んでたわ
それは　レアケースだね
That's... quite a rarity.
Anyway, let's take another look at this movie.
まあとにかく　あの映画をもう一度見てみようよ
海藤
Kaitou!
ちち　血だ
B-B-Blood!
ぎゃー
ちょ　ちょっと　あれ
H-Hey, is that...
やっぱりこの　海藤先輩の腕は見事よね
Kaitou's arm was really well done.
It really does look like an arm.
ちゃんと腕に見えるもん
The prop guys were the most talented part of the team, I guess.
結局一番有能だったのは　小道具班だったのかな
Damn it! Who did this?
But...
そんな
やっぱりそんなに大したトリックには見えないけどな
I really can't imagine this being some kind of complicated twist.
ああ　難しいものを簡単そうに見せている
Yeah. It's disguised to look simple.
違うわよ
No.
これが簡単そうに見えるのは　そう仕組まれたからじゃないわ
It wasn't intended to look simple.
Then what?
なら
私が思うにね　このビデオが映像としてつまらなくて
I think it's because the movie itself is so boring
that it makes the mystery seem uninteresting as well.
見る人の興味をそそらないから謎が引き立たないのよ
ほう
二年Ｆ組の有志は　カンヤ祭への参加を決め
A number of volunteers from Class 2-F decided to take part in the Kan'ya fair.
確かにね　僕も初見ではこれが密室殺人だと暫く気付かなかったくらいだよ
They are currently on their way to the Narakubo area to gather material for their exhibition.
Yeah, it took me a while to realize it was a locked room mystery.
We're still not there?
Yamanishi      Midori
その方面の演出が弱いからね
In that way, their performance is quite lacking.
What do you mean?
We're close. Should only be about five more minutes.
たとえば
The camera work's pretty bad.
カメラワークが悪い
That's exactly what you said last time!
Yeah, that's it!
そう　それ
なら　伊原ならどう撮る
Then how would you do it, Ibara?
Me?
私なら
It's quite ti—
Let me see...
そうね
For example, here.
たとえば　えっと
ここよ
It's full of du—
埃っぽっ
Wouldn't it be better to frame this shot from further away, to show off more of the hall with the actors?
ここ　もっと引いた所から　登場人物と館内を一緒に映した方が効果的じゃない
Yeah.
確かに
それから　こことか
And...
here as well.
Hey, Sugimura! Had any luck up there?
おおい　杉村　そっちはどうだ
This one's quite clean. We could use it.
割と綺麗だよ　使えるかもしれない
I'll come back dow—
ここ 杉村先輩の視点から撮った方が
And here, if they took this shot from Sugimura's point of view,
it'd be much clearer that he was overseeing the lobby.
ロビーが監視下にあったって分かりやすかったと思う
カメラがロビーから見上げてじゃ　観客に伝わらないでしょう
The viewers don't get that when the shot's taken from ground level.
えっと　他にはね
Oh, and also...
Sorry, that's enough.
ごめん　もういいよ
Why?
どうして
We could do this all day.
きりがない
映像の拙さにけちをつけても始まらん
We'll get nowhere if we just complain about technical issues.
まあまあ　ちょっと検討してもいいかもね
Yeah, yeah. It might still be worth considering, though.
見つけたぞ　福部
Found you, Fukube!
こんな所で油売りやがって
What are you doing, messing around over here?!
Ah, hello, Yamaguchi! Welcome!
やあ山内くん　ようこそ
Hey, violence isn't the answer, you know?
ちよ　ちょっと乱暴はよしたまえ
I'm doing this for your sake!
俺はお前のためを思ってやってるんだ
Yeah, but I have my own priorities too!
でも　僕にも色々とやるべきことが
What's wrong with you? You think Omichi was kidding around?!
馬鹿　尾道は本気だぞ
進級できなくなってもいいのか
Are you trying to get kept down a year?!
里志よ　補習なら受けたほうがいいぞ
Satoshi, you should take your supplementary classes more seriously.
B-But Hongou's mystery is important too!
でも　本郷先輩の謎かけも大事だよ
奉太郎　今すぐちょいちょいと片づけてよ
Houtarou, quickly, figure it out right now!
What are you talking about?!
何訳の分からんこと言ってるんだ
But you know—
いや　これはね
No! That secret! That locked room!
いやだ　僕はあの秘密を　密室がぁ
行っちゃった
There he goes.
I don't know what's wrong with that guy.
バカかあいつは
Here he comes.
戻ってきた
Please, Houtarou.
無念だ奉太郎　ままならぬは世間のしがらみだよ
It's depressing when you realize that some things are just beyond our control.
Now that it's come to this,
斯くなる上は
福部
Fukube!
this notebook will have to carry on in my place!
このメモ帳を僕だと思ってくれ
ほら　行くぞ
Come on already!
I get it, I'm going!
分かってる　行くって
またっく
For the love of...
Time I got going too.
さてっと
私も行かないと
そうか
Oh?
何を　その目は
What's with that look?
私は入須先輩ならともかく
I can't help you right now, not even for Irisu's sake.
あんたを手伝う気はないんだから
And why is that?
さいて
図書当番よ
I've got library duty.
I'd have kept today open if I'd known this was going to happen.
こんなことになるって分かってたら
あらかじめ予定を開けておいたのに
いきなり言い出すあんたが悪いのよ
It's your fault for springing it on us like that.
Though...
でも　ごめんね折木
Sorry, Oreki.
さって
All right.
Let's split up and check the building.
手分けして　中を調べよう
えっ
畜生　誰が
Damn it! Who did this?
B-B-Blood!
ちち　血だ
それなら大丈夫
That won't be a problem. The keys should be here.
ええ
きっとあると思う
ぎゃー
I see.
そうか
これが　本郷の真意だ
So this was Hongou's true intention.
处暑
暑将退
伏而潜处 故名也
Limit of Heat
As the Sun's strength falters,
summer's feverish heat breaks for the first time.
Hyouka
Come in.
どうぞ
まず聞きたい
My first question is: have you figured it out?
結論は出たか
I see. Then please elaborate.
そう　では聞こう
はい
This mystery clearly hinges on the locked room.
あの謎のキーになるのは　言うまでもなく密室です
That guy – I mean, Kaitou – died in a room
海藤が　あ　いえ
海藤先輩が死んでいた部屋には
where no one could enter or leave.
あのメンバーの誰も入れなかったし　出ることも出来なかった
先輩はなくてもいい
Don't worry about the formalities.
The left wing was a locked room.
上手袖は密室です
畜生　だれが！
Damn it! Who did this?
The only connection to the outside was the window, and as you can see...
唯一外と繋がる窓もこの状態です
Left Wing
Waiting Room
Hall
Stage
Right wing
...the culprit had no choice but to use the door.
となると　犯人はドアから出入りしたとしか考えられません
But how?
では　どうやってか
From the video we have no way of knowing if there was some kind of physical trick to the door,
あのドアに物理的トリックがあるかどうか映像からはわかりません
so the most logical conclusion is that the culprit used the master key.
ならば　犯人はマスターキーを持って出入りしたと考えるのが一番妥当です
しかし　ロビーは杉村の監視下にあります
However, Sugimura was watching the lobby.
Office
Reception
1st Floor
Entrance Lobby
Toilet
Waiting
Room
そのため　犯人は右側通路にすら入れません
For that reason, the culprit wouldn't even be able to use the right-hand corridor.
It is, in essence, the second "locked room".
これが第二の密室です
Office
Reception
1st Floor
Entrance Lobby
Toilet
Waiting
Room
Not one of the six characters could have taken the master key from the office and entered the corridor.
事務室でマスターキーを入手し
それから　右側通路に入れる人間は六人の中にはいません
What does that mean?
それなら　どういうことになるか
六人の中に犯人がいないのなら　結論は一つ
If the culprit wasn't one of those six, there's only one explanation.
There must have been a seventh person.
あの場には七人目がいたんです
A seventh person? Like Sawakiguchi predicted?
七人目？
沢木口の言うように？
Yes.
はい
At first it sounded pretty ridiculous,
これを思いついたときは随分荒唐無稽だと思いましたが
but if what she said is correct, Hongou was looking for a seventh actor.
沢木口によると　本郷は七人目の登場人物を探していたそうです
Remembering that was what cemented this idea in my mind.
それを思い出して　俺は確信しました
Hongou wrote this script according to the rules, though.
でも　本郷はあの脚本をフェアに書いたということです
I don't think she'd have some kind of slasher pop up out of nowhere.
突然現れた怪人とは考えられません
There were a few more things in the video that didn't add up.
ところで　映像に奇妙な点が何点かありました
Satoshi noted them here.
里志がそのことを書いています
When Kounosu finds the floor plan, it's lit up. Probably from a flashlight.
鴻巣　見取り図を見つける
照明当たる
懐中電灯と思われる
And then, when they go to look for Kaitou...
もう一箇所　海藤を探しにいくところです
The corridor is dim and poorly lit. They use a flashlight there, too.
通路暗し　光量不足
懐中電灯を使われる
A flashlight?
懐中電灯か
Yes. But none of the main actors carried one.
そうです
そして登場人物の誰も懐中電灯を持ってはいないんです
You can see this from the scenes right after it's used,
懐中電灯の光があたったシーンの直後
for instance when they first enter the crime scene.
たとえば　事件現場突入直後なんかの映像を見ればはっきりわかります
They had time to hide the flashlight, but there'd be no logical reason for them to do so.
懐中電灯を隠す時間はありましたが
そうする合理的理由はないでしょ
I know, you can say that it's just a matter of lighting.
わかります　あれは照明だと言いたいんでしょう？
But before that, please keep this in mind.
でも　まずはこの件を覚えておいてください
And this is something I'm saying as a movie enthusiast, so please don't be offended.
もうひとつ　映画好きの奴の言葉ですが　気を悪くしないでください
This movie is boring. The acting is bad.
あの映画はつまらなかった　演出が悪い
The camera work in particular is extremely amateurish.
特にカメラワークは全然工夫がなかったと
But if that was on purpose...
けれど　もしそれも理由のあることだったら？
The cameraman was filming from the six actors' point of view.
この映画　カメラマンは常に六人と同じ立ち位置から撮影していました
I think you get it already.
もう分かったと思いますが
Are you telling me...
まさか　君はカメラマンが第七の人物だと言うつもりか
The cameraman was the seventh actor?
There were seven of them from the very beginning.
彼らは最初から七人だったんです
The six actors who appeared on screen,
画面に出てくる六人と
and the cameraman who filmed them.
カメラでそれを撮影している一人の　計七人
Seven in total.
Look at this. The actors glance at the camera every now and then.
見てください
ところどころで役者がカメラを気にする場面が出てきます
It's not safe to sleep here—
They are conscious of the camera's presence.
彼らはそこにいるカメラマンを意識していたんです
It's not right to call him the cameraman, so let's call him the seventh character.
カメラマンと言うと語弊がある
「七人目」と言いましょうか
It's not unusual to consider there'd be someone holding that flashlight.
懐中電灯の照明については
それを持つ人物がいると考えても不自然じゃない
The camera work is bad because he can't film the same scene from various points of view.
カメラワークの下手さも
彼があちこちから同時に一つのシーンを撮ることが出来ない存在
It makes sense to consider him an actor.
つまり　役者だからと考えれば頷けます
そして　これが重要なんですが
And here's the important part.
The camera stayed in the lobby until everyone else left, then the scene was cut.
メンバーが劇場内部に散ったとき
カメラは誰もいなくなるまでロビーにありました
そしてシーンがアウトした
Which meant that the camera was stopped and left waiting for the others to return to the lobby.
つまり　一時的にカメラが止められた後
カメラはロビーで戻ってくるメンバーを待っていたんです
Therefore, the crime is simple.
故に犯行は簡単です
The seventh character waited for everyone else to vanish into the theater,
七人目は全員が劇場内に散るのを待ち
stopped the camera, quickly took the master key from the office,
手に持ったカメラを止めると
速やかに事務室のマスターキーを入手
killed Kaitou, then locked the room using the key.
海藤を殺した後　それを使って部屋を閉じます
Then he waited in the lobby for the others to return.
そして　ロビーで他のメンバーが戻ってくるのを待ったんです
That is my conclusion.
以上が結論です
If Hongou has yet to choose a seventh actor, I'd suggest you do so quickly.
本郷が七人目の役者をまだ選んでいないのなら
早急にそれを用意することをお勧めします
Two problems.
ふたつある
Firstly, if this character existed,
まずひとつ
もしそうなら
wouldn't it be strange that he never says a word, and none of the others speak to him?
七人目は一言も喋らず声もかけられないというのは不自然ではないか
Hongou might've considered that as the motive.
本郷はそれを動機にしたのかもしれません
The seventh character is always ignored by the other six.
七人目は他の六人に無視される存在でした
And that's why he never talked to them, either.
彼はそれ故自分から口を開くこともできなかった
Secondly, the people in the theater would be able to figure this out instantly.
もうひとつ
もしそうならば　劇中の彼らは遠からず結論に辿り着けるはず
Surely anyone would suspect this seventh character who supposedly stayed in the lobby all along.
ずっとロビーにいた七人目を疑わない者はない
さらに　君の言う第二の密室は破られていない
Not to mention that the second "locked room"
you mentioned is still a factor.
We can assume that the actors could see the seventh character moving around.
七人目の移動する姿は衆人環視のもとにあったと推定できる
それなら　犯人はすぐ分かると思うが
Therefore, the culprit would be obvious.
As Sawakiguchi would put it,
沢木口の言葉を借りましょう
"Who cares about a witness or two?"
別にいいでしょ　それくらい
It makes no difference if the characters figure it out right away.
登場人物にゃ分かりきったことでも構わない
The important part is making the viewers wonder about the mystery, right?
観客が謎に悩みさえすればそれでいいと思いませんか
Maybe that's why there's no detective role in the script itself.
だから　あの脚本には探偵役がいないのかもしれない
It's because the culprit is clear to the characters,
作中の奴らには推理する必要もなく
without them even having to think about it.
犯人は明らかだからです
Congratulations.
おめでとう
Looks like you've solved Hongou's mystery.
君は本郷の謎を解いたようだな
I was somewhat taken aback by your daring conclusion,
まったく驚くべき大胆な発想だが
but as it fits all the facts, it must be right.
すべての事実に一致する以上　それが正しい事は間違いない
And... thank you.
そして　ありがとう
Now we can finally complete the movie.
これで映画は完成する
I was right after all.
やはり私の目に狂いはなかったようだ
You have talent.
君には技術があった　ほかの誰にもない力が
A power possessed by no other.
Uh... Thank you.
いや　その…　恐縮です
Why don't you decide the title of the movie?
どうだろう　あの映画のタイトルをつけてみないか
The title?
タイトル？
Anything you can think of.
即興でいい
We'd all be happy with any idea you have.
君が考えてくれれば　みんなも喜ぶと思うのだが
Huh...
Let's see... Something that fits the movie...
そうですね
内容に即して
How about "Out of Sight, Out of Mind"?
「万人の死角」というのはどうでしょう
That's a great title! Let's go with that!
いいタイトルだ　それに決めよう
Home run.
ホームラン～
おはようございまーす
Everyone in third year...
ええ　三年生の皆さんは
With the culture fair in October...
十月には文化祭もありますので
There is a preview
screening of the movie
in the media room.
I'm going ahead.
Chitanda
I can't imagine how anyone could have entered that room.
やっぱり　誰もあの部屋に近づけたとは思えない
No one could have.
そうだな　ただ一人
Except for one person: you.
お前を除けばだが
You did it?
お前がやったのか
It was you?
あんたがやったの？
How could you?
なんてこと
Why? Just why?!
お前なんでこんな
Yeah!
I didn't see that coming.
びっくりしたよね
Hey, wait!
おい　待てよ
Trying to run away?!
逃げんのか
Don't think you can escape!
観念しなさい
That was really cool!
Damn, that was one hell of an ending!
まったく　本当にすごいラストだったな
Looks like it was a success.
リアル海藤だ
Yeah, to think it was the cameraman!
まさかカメラマンとはね
Hey! I heard ya figured it out in the end.
よお　聞いたよ
結局お前が考えてくれたんだってな
Well, yeah...
ええ　まあ
Hell, that endin' sure threw me fer a loop!
いやあ　あのオチは驚いた　文句なしだ
Well done!
Hey, Mr. Ace Detective!
やあ～　名探偵君～
Ace detective?
名探偵って
Awesome job!
やってくれるじゃん
Though, it sure is a shame that the seventh character didn't like,
まあ　七人目がばれたところで
凶暴化して全員に襲い掛からなかったのは残念だけどね
go nuts and massacre the rest of 'em when they found him out!
Yeah...
Anyway, much 'bliged!
まあ　ときかくありがとな
Laters!
それじゃあ
Sure...
はい
By the way, Nakajou!
しっかし　中城
What?
なんだい？
Your armpits reek.
腋汗すごいね
Eh?!
Pretty nice, huh?
Don't you shower?
Shut up!
I guess Haba wasn't a fan.
どうやら羽場はお気に召さなかったようだ
Houtarou!
奉太郎
We saw it too.
見たよ
How was it?
どうだった？
うん　悪くない
Not bad.
It was interesting. Didn't expect it to be the cameraman.
面白かったよ
まさかカメラマンとはね
Is this what you were thinking earlier?
この前のときにもうこんなこと考えてたの？
I hadn't come up with it by that point.
あのときは考えついてなかった
Is that so?
そう
Huh? They don't seem surprised at all.
That's Houtarou for you.
（さすが奉太郎といったところだね）
なんだ　あまり驚いてないな
Yeah. Annoying as ever.
（そうね　悔しいけど）
Well, I guess this is it.
ま　こんなものか
Oreki!
折木さん
Huh?
I...
私…
Um...
えっと…
I'll tell you later!
あとでです
Anyway, well done, Houtarou!
まあ　とにかく上出来だよ　奉太郎
The movie's finished and the Empress approves.
女帝も満足　映画は完成
And the viewers seem to like the surprise ending as well.
この意外性なら　観客も楽しんでくれそうだ
Oreki.
折木
I've got a question.
ちょっと聞きたいんだけど
What?
何だ？
Hey!
おいおい
So you came up with that conclusion?
あの解決は折木が出したのよね
That's right.
そうだが
The whole thing?
全部？
I guess.
多分
Then what do you think of what Haba said?
じゃあ　あんたは羽場先輩の言ったことをどう考えたの？
Haba?
羽場の？
Um...
あの
The rope didn't show up in the movie.
あの映画の中にはどこにもザイルが出てこなかったわよ
今夜恋に変わる　幸せな夢で会おう
Let us meet in a blissful dream tonight, let it be our love
きっと　ねぇ見つけてね
Find me, I beg you
まどろみの約束
We promised to meet, drifting in and out of sleep
芽生えてた温もり　暖かくて戸惑う
This sprouting warmth confuses us
こんな気持ちをまだ　あなたは分からないよ
Don't you understand this feeling yet?
そんな視線には意味なんて　別にないはず
Normally such random glances hold no meaning
だって友達にしてるのと同じ
Isn't it the same when making friends?
明け方に消えてく　小さな願星
The little shooting stars we wish upon, vanishing into the dawn
夜の間だけの魔法を…
are a magic that only unfolds in the night
今夜恋に変わる　幸せな夢で会おう
Let us meet in a blissful dream tonight, let it be our love
きっと　ねぇ見つけてね
Find me, I beg you
まどろみの約束
We promised to meet, drifting in and out of sleep
Next time: Fools' Staff Roll.
次回　愚者のエンドロール
Fools' Staff Roll